<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.danielvartan.netlogo</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>NetLogo</name>
  <summary>A multi-agent programmable modeling environment</summary>
  <icon type="stock">com.danielvartan.netlogo.NetLogo</icon>
  <description>
    <p>
      NetLogo is a powerful, easy-to-learn programmable modeling environment for
      simulating natural and social phenomena through agent-based modeling, used
      in both research and education. It was authored by Uri Wilensky in 1999
      and has been in continuous development ever since at the Center for
      Connected Learning and Computer-Based Modeling.
    </p>
    <p>
      NetLogo is particularly well suited for modeling complex systems
      developing over time. Modelers can give instructions to hundreds or
      thousands of “agents” all operating independently. This makes it possible
      to explore the connection between the micro-level behavior of individuals
      and the macro-level patterns that emerge from their interaction.
    </p>
    <p>
      NetLogo lets students open simulations and “play” with them, exploring
      their behavior under various conditions. It is also an authoring
      environment which enables students, teachers and curriculum developers to
      create their own models. NetLogo is simple enough for students and
      teachers, yet advanced enough to serve as a powerful tool for researchers
      in many fields.
    </p>
    <p>
      NetLogo has extensive documentation and tutorials. It also comes with the
      Models Library, a large collection of pre-written simulations that can be
      used and modified. These simulations address content areas in the natural
      and social sciences including biology and medicine, physics and chemistry,
      mathematics and computer science, and economics and social psychology.
      Several model-based inquiry curricula using NetLogo are available and more
      are under development.
    </p>
    <p>
      NetLogo is the next generation of the series of multi-agent modeling
      languages including StarLogo and StarLogoT. NetLogo runs on the Java
      Virtual Machine, so it works on all major platforms (Mac, Windows, Linux,
      et al). It is run as a desktop application. Command line operation is also
      supported.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.danielvartan.netlogo.NetLogo.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.netlogo.org</url>
  <provides>
    <binary>NetLogo</binary>
    <binary>NetLogo3D</binary>
    <binary>HubNetClient</binary>
    <binary>Behaviorsearch</binary>
    <binary>netlogo</binary>
    <binary>netlogo3d</binary>
    <binary>hubnetclient</binary>
    <binary>behaviorsearch</binary>
    <mediatype>application/x-netlogo</mediatype>
    <mediatype>application/x-behaviorsearch</mediatype>
  </provides>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>Science</category>
  </categories>
  <mimetypes>
    <mimetype>application/x-netlogo</mimetype>
    <mimetype>application/x-behaviorsearch</mimetype>
  </mimetypes>
  <releases>
    <release version="7.0.3" date="2025-12-01"/>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
